welcome to subramany.com
i'm going to give you
10 easy steps to create wealth
you see what works for you
and let me also tell you these are not
mine i'll tell you whose chips these are
so lot of young people
would like to know how to get rich
what they don't tell you is how to reach
get rich quickly
the question is not just how to get rich
so that is a little difficult
and i have always held that you can be
rich you can be wealthy but it takes
time
but the problem is they don't want to be
sitting in the alps and having coffee
they want to be skiing in the alps so
skiing in the alps means you have to go
in your twenties
uh maybe in your thirties but not
definitely not in your sixties at six in
c you can ski in your sixties provided
you've been skiing right from your
twenties and thirties suddenly you're
not going to learn right so i said okay
so there is this author called ken
fisher who is apart from being an author
i mean far more famous as a fund manager
and
he's also written books but yeah and
another claim to famous is phil fisher's
son
and if you've read books by phil fisher
great if you have not read you should go
and read it so he says there are only 10
roads to
wealth
and
he enumerates those 10 roads and i i'll
talk about those 10 roads and because
i'm going to talk about it i'm going to
read i'll read the road and then i'll
tell you so
first is the route which many successful
people have taken like bill gates and
all
that set up your own business
take the company public that is the
finest way to create a lot of wealth
because it means
you're running a business you're earning
one rupee and the market gives you a p
of 30
so therefore you suddenly get valued at
30 times of what you have done so this
is the route which most people or many
people take
and uday kotak
mr motila
mr
motel
and ramdevagarwal nirmal jain rashesha
all these people have taken that route
of ah or you take narayan murthy you
take any of these people this is what
they did they set up a successful
business and then they went and got it
listed the minute you get listed you get
a high
valuation of say 10 20 pe or 30 pe
so every rupee that you want gets the
respect of 30 times and therefore you
get rich that is the first one
second one is become the ceo of an
existing firm and
get a very high salary not everybody is
able to do it
but some people have been able to do it
a jack welch did it
nike at
lnt did it there are many others who are
there this does create wealth but not
that kind of wealth which the first one
creates where being the owner and having
a listed company creates but this also
creates good wealth these days
uh
many ceos get paid well in the region of
five six crores maybe even 10 crores and
i'm not talking of owner ceos i'm
talking of professional ceos
third
the nice one is to hitch on with a
successful guy so
i'm a techie guy and so i just go and
hitch with one of these
persons mentioned in the first one
that nirmal jain for example is not a
tech person right he's a chartered
accountant mba so i go and become his
tech person is number two and then i
create wealth for myself too not as much
wealth as uh the promoter creates for
himself
but yeah the golden dust falls on you
too so if he may create some 3000 crores
for himself you end up creating 40 50
crores for yourself and that's not too
bad
considering creating that kind of wealth
with a job is not going to be very easy
so if he is good enough and parts with
more money maybe you create 100 crores
for yourself so that is the third one
fourth of course is
turn
celebrity into well you become a
celebrity you get
you play a sport of course this needs
tremendous talent it's not easy to say
pick up a bat and become a sanji sachin
tendulkar or move some pieces of
horses and
elephants and become a vishwanath
no it's not going to be going to happen
so easily but yes that's another way of
hitting big time good reaches thousand
crores plus kind of net worth
the fourth or the fifth one is of course
a very well or thought of old strategy
marry very well see being poor is bad
luck
if your father is poor it's bad luck but
if your father-in-law is also poor
it is bad planning you should have
planned better so if you are not married
try marrying a rich girl and if you are
a rich girl who is not admired try
marrying a rich boy this works
we have to end and then see what works
for whom
the other one is to set up your own
business and steal money no guns needed
nothing
no gun license
there are enough number of banks and
investors willing to part with money
musketeer you can really have a nice
comfortable life
taking money from a lot of people
but continuously take money every three
four years you take some money and say
this will work that will work and you
know so call it equity
call it debt if you call it debt
remember to pay interest and repay the
loan and make sure that those checks
don't bounce you can always go get
people to
say you're a startup and people will
give you money and you can start that at
25 and go until 65 that's not a problem
that makes money
legally without any guns or a knife or
anything
capitalize on other people's money where
most of the mega rich are you really get
into very good top quality fund
management opm that is other people's
money makes a lot of money ken fisher is
one of them
right so money managing makes more money
than money itself so get into money
management if you can do that well and
handle say
10 000 crores you can make 100 crores
for yourself and 10 000 crores managing
doesn't seem to be very difficult today
there are 42 mutual funds in india and
all of them married and manage more than
10 000 crores so yeah so that's not
impossible to do
monetize a lot of your real estate which
your father has left or your grandfather
has left and you know it's not uh
i mean what a hiranandani has done for
him
has done for himself what a pirate have
done for himself right so largely you
could do that
or you could come to the tenth most
important step the one which works for
me
and which will work for you is save well
okay let me go one step
study well get a good job say well
invest smartly
do an sip or whatever learn about
equities and start doing equity
investments
that is the way which work for me you
have to see which of these 10 ways will
work for you
do accordingly
to me the 10th is the one which work so
i will stick to 10 i couldn't fit into
any of the other things so i'm happy
with my formula study well on well
invest well and that will create wealth
for you that's what works for me right
thank you